Muhammad Hazim Bin Sulaiman, Aspiring Software Developer

+6597221283 hazim897@gmail.com hajimss.github.io linkedin.com/in/muhammad-hazim-bin-sulaiman-3386191a0

Executive Summary

Software Engineering / Web Development Enthusiast, who develops websites, applications, artificial intelligence as hobby. Currently working as a Software Developer and does side projects related to information technology (IT) after work. Enjoys both frontend and backend development. Continuously learns libraries and frameworks associated with Python, C++, Javascript.

Previously, a firefighter who served the community, and a mechanical engineer in offshore, oil & gas technology.

Relevant Experience

UBS, Software Engineer

- Technologies used: Python, Web2py, Pandas, Jupyter etc
- Handled Data Analytics and Data workflows (ETL)
- Created Proof of concept for the application of Apache Kafka on the Change Data Capture of server network

NUS FintechSG Programme

- Frontend and Backend Web development (Javascript, React, Database: MySQL, MongoDB), and Containerisation
- Data Analytics and AlgoTrading (QuantConnect)
- UI/UX on Figma
- Blockchain (Smart Contracts using Solidity)

IOT/Robotics Engineer with Catalyst Connector Pte Ltd (Design Project)

- Led a team of six to build an autonomous grass-cutting robot
- Supervised shell modelling and manufacturing, using Solidworks and machineries;
 implemented structural analysis with Ansys
- Deployed autopilot using QGroundControl and Pixhawk4

Education

July 2020

Introduction to Fintech, Hong Kong University on edX (HKUx)

- Online course that provides introductory knowledge on FinTech

Aug 2016 - May 2020

Bachelor of Engineering (Mechanical Engineering), National University of Singapore

- Specialised in Offshore Oil & Gas Technology
- GPA: 3.83
- Relevant coursework: Fluid Mechanics, Strength of Materials, Manufacturing Processes,
 Engineering Innovation and Modelling, Engineering Thermodynamics, Robot Mechanics
- Technical electives: Programming Methodology (C), Data Structures and Algorithms (C++)

Jul 2018 – Aug 2018

Summer Exchange, Hanyang University (Korea)

- Modules: Heat Transfer & Calculus

Flask Familiarisation App

- Deployed a journaling app to check progress in learning Flask
- Connected to MongoDB Atlas as database
- Integrated a csv to dataframe function within site using Pandas.
- App URL: https://hazimisusingflaskandmongo.herokuapp.com/home
- Git Repository: https://github.com/hajimss/flask-and-mongo

Tensorflow Chatbot

- Designed a chatbot webapp that will respond to queries and greetings
- Utilised neural network functions and libraries from tensorflow and tflearn
- Frontend: React; Backend: Flask
- App URL: http://chatboy2020.herokuapp.com/
- Git Repository: https://github.com/hajimss/chatbot

Work Experience

Oct 2020 - Present

Software Engineering, UBS

- Department: Network Services and Automation
- Analyse data of worldwide UBS servers and render solutions to optimise usage

Jul 2018 – Dec 2018

Mechanical Engineer (Intern), Schlumberger (Singapore Well Testing Centre - SWTC)

- Supported SWTC's new product development department
- Created CAD (Computer-Aided Design) models, assemblies and drawings and assisted in physical assembles

May 2014 – Jun 2016

Firefighter (NS), Singapore Civil Defence Force

- Performed firefighting and rescue operations as a firefighter
- Responsible for logistics and equipment maintenance of firefighting equipment within station

Co-Curricular Participation

Mechanical Engineering Camp Committee

- Safety officer; supervised and kept a lookout for potential risks and its probability involved during camp activities and ensured hazards are kept at a minimum

Temasek Hall (2016 - 2020)

- Main Committee of Sports Management Board;
- Participated in Floorball, Soccer and Touch Rugby for Inter-Hall Games 2017, 2018, 2019 &
 2020
- Member of Vox (Chorale and Acapella group) Temasek Hall (2020 present)
- Class Ambassador; initiates gathering of alumnus for upcoming hall events

Skills

Languages: English and Malay

Software Programming: Python (Pandas and Flask), C, C++, Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, React, Git, Apache Kafka, MySQL, MongoDB